（信(しん)）ハッ… ンンッ！
今 急に空気が変わった
The air suddenly changed just now...
There's something past here...
この先に何かいる
（尾平(びへい)）おい 信！ どうした？
Hey, Xin!
What's going on?!
（歩兵）こ… こら 貴様！
先導車を抜くな！
H-Hey, you!
Don't go in front of the guide chariot!
It's getting hotter and hotter...
どんどん熱くなる
It's getting heavier and heavier...
どんどん重くなる
What is this feeling?
何だ？ この感じ
すぐ目の前に 何か いやがる
There's something coming up soon!
Something huge!
とんでもねえ何かが！
（信）な… 何だ こりゃ！
Wh-What is this?!
（斬る音）
（歩兵たち）ウワッ！
（尾平･尾到(びとう)）アア…
So this... is a battlefield?!
戦場か これが…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
Timing
Seboo
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
Typesetting
rtrs
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I knew at the start that there's no end.
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Threat of the Chariot Corps
The State of Qin and the State of Wei.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秦国 魏国(ぎこく)
その両国の国境近くにある滎陽(けいよう)の地
Lying near the borders of those two kingdoms is the land called Rongyang.
Qin
Wei
そこは 魏国の西の玄関口であり
戦略上の重要拠点である
As an entryway to the State of Wei, it is an important strategic location.
Rongyang
Over this location,
その滎陽を巡り 両国間で
ついに 戦いの火蓋が切られた
the flame of war between both countries was finally lit.
Rongyang
Wan Castle
Yashui
With Yashui as their troop headquarters, the Qin Army tried to attack Rongyang from three locations.
亜水(あすい)を本陣とし ３か所から―
滎陽を攻めようとした
秦軍に対し
Qin Army Supreme Commander Biao Gong
Xi Castle
隰城(しょうじょう)から打って出た
魏軍総大将 呉慶(ごけい)は
To oppose them, the Wei Army Commander, Wu Qing, attacked from Xi Castle.
Rongyang
Wan Castle
Yashui
With lightning speed, he put the State of Qin on the defensive.
電撃の早さで
Wei Army Supreme Commander Wu Qing
秦国の守りを
逆に食い破っていく
For Xin and the others at the mercy of their armies in their first campaign,
歩兵として
初陣を迎えた信たちは
それに翻弄され
Rongyang
Yashui
their destination was changed from Wan Castle to Yashui
目標の地を丸城(がんじょう) 亜水と変えつつ
and now they have finally reached the location of the deciding battle,
ようやく 決戦の地“蛇甘(だかん)平原”に
たどりついたのだった
Shegan Plain
the Shegan Plain.
Thousand-Man General Fu Hushen
4th Army, line up!
（縛虎申(ばくこしん)）
第４軍 整列！
俺は 千人将 縛虎申！
これより軍編成が始まる
I am Thousand-Man General Fu Hushen!
The organizing of troops will now begin!
伍(ご)は１列に整列せよ！
All Wu, form a line!
（尾平）どうなってんだよ…
城攻めじゃなかったのかよ？
What's going on...?
We're not sieging a castle...?
Hurry and line up, you bastards!
（縛虎申）
さっさと並ばんか 貴様ら！
（百人将）お待ちください 千人将
我らは 合流地が亜水から―
Please wait, Thousand-Man General!
Our union point is set to be Yashui,
この蛇甘平原に変わったことしか
聞かされておりません
though I am hearing nothing but different reports here at the Shegan Plain.
秦軍は 滎陽を
攻める予定ではなかったのですか？
Is the Qin Army no longer planning to attack Rongyang?
歩兵ごときが
戦の全容を知る必要はない！
There is no need for a common soldier to know the entirety of the scenario!
貴様らは
上官の命令どおり戦えばよいのだ
All you need to do is obey the orders of your superior officers!
し… しかし 我らは…
B-But we...
ヒイッ！
（どよめき）
（壁(へき)）待て！
Wait!
（壁）今の
目まぐるしく変わっている戦況は
In this hectic and changing progression of war,
たとえ歩兵でも説明してやるべきだ
we should explain the situation even to foot soldiers.
（尾平）あれは…
That's... the Thousand-Man General from the other day?
この間の千人将？
（信）壁…
Bi...
新参者が出しゃばるな
（壁）新参だろうと関係ない
Don't interfere, newcomer!
My experience is irrelevant!
千人将同士
遠慮なく意見させてもらう
Let us discuss things unreservedly as fellow Thousand-Man Generals.
なに？
What?!
（尚鹿(しょうかく)）
そう熱くなるなよ ２人とも
兵たちの前で みっともないぞ
Don't get so heated, you two.
It's disgraceful in front of the soldiers.
Shut your trap, Shang Lu.
うせろ 尚鹿　今こいつと話してる
I'm talking with him right now!
（尚鹿）そうもいかんな
こいつとは幼なじみでな
I can't do that either.
Thousand-Man General Shang Lu
This guy's a childhood friend of mine.
And usually a conversation has two people listening to the other.
大体 話は２人で
聞くことになってる
Hey.
（縛虎申）おい
ふざけてると ２人とも殺すぞ
If you screw around, I'm gonna kill the two of you.
魏の軍は 我らの虚を突き
滎陽から打って出た
The Wei Army attacked us from Rongyang when we were unguarded!
それに対して我らも 本軍を
亜水から この蛇甘平原に進めた
In response to that, we have progressed our main army to the Shegan Plain!
Both armies confronted each other and started to battle yesterday!
両軍 対峙(たいじ)し
開戦したのは昨日のことだ
The 3rd, 5th, and 6th armies have yet to arrive at the plain.
第３ ５ ６軍は
いまだ 平原には至っておらず―
Our army is at a disadvantage to the opposing army's numbers!
我が軍は
その数において不利である
And since the Wei Army arrived on top of that hill before us by a small margin,
また 丘の上は―
僅かの差で 先に到着した魏軍に
ことごとく布陣され地形的にも不利
in regard to our terrain and battle formations, we are also entirely at a disadvantage!
勝利のためには
丘を取ることが必要だ
The only way to gain victory is to take that hill!
現在 第２軍が戦っているが
見てのとおり苦戦中
The 2nd army is currently fighting, but as you can see, it's a tough battle!
Our reinforcements are waiting!
我らの援軍を待っている
我ら第４軍は
軍編成ののち 第２軍を助け―
We, the 4th army, after unit formations, will aid the 2nd army
and capture that hill under any circumstances!
なんとしても
あの丘を奪取せねばならん
これが今の全状況である
That is the situation in its entirety!
丘を取りゃいいのか
分かりやすくていいぜ
So we just need to take the hill?
Good, that's easy enough to understand.
（壁）大秦国の兵士は
全中華が恐れる勇猛な兵士である
The soldiers of the great State of Qin are brave men feared by all of China!
血を流すことを惜しむな
死ぬことを惜しむな
Do not be reluctant to spill blood!
Do not be reluctant to kill!
As long as strength remains in your bodies, cut, cut, cut them all down!
力続くかぎり
斬って斬って 斬りまくれ！
魏の兵の血で 平原を赤く染めよ！
諸君らの武運を祈る！
Paint the plain red with the blood of Wei soldiers!
Gentleman, I wish you all the fortunes of war!
（縛虎申）第４軍 縛虎申隊 整列！
4th army, Fu Hushen unit, line up!
( Flag - Qin )
Of all people...
（尾平）よりによって―
あのおっかねえ千人将の隊に
入れられちまった…
we ended up in that scary Thousand-Man Generals' unit...?
I've heard he's a guy who puts people into brutal battles...
（尾到）
ひでえ戦いさせる人だって聞くし
（ツバを飲む音）
おまけに…
And on top of that...
最前列 …と来たか
We came to... the front line...
（斬る音）
（歩兵たち）ウワッ！
W-We're about to go into that mess, too?!
い… 今から
あの中に俺たちも入るのか？
（せきこみ）
兄貴…
Big Bro!
（脇次(きょうじ)）情けねえヤツらだ
What a pathetic lot...
（脇次）しかし 相変わらず
この待ちの間は たまんねえな
But just as always, I really can't stand waiting here.
（筏建(ばつけん)）まったくだ
Seriously!
（澤圭(たくけい)）最前列の多くは
最初の衝突で命を落とします
Most people in the front line lose their lives in the first collision.
（澤圭）なんとか頑張って
そこを乗り切りましょう
Let's just do our best and try to get through it.
It's no use, Wuchang...
（尾平）ムリだよ 伍長…
Even if we get past the first wave,
最初を乗り切ったとしても
あの混戦じゃ弱い俺らは死んじまう
weak guys like us will die in that melee...
It'll be all right.
大丈夫です　混戦になれば
僅かですが 私の経験が生きます
If it does turn into a melee, though it'll just be a little, my experience will be a help.
Experience?
（尾平）経験？
はい　私の伍は
いつも最弱といわれてますが
Yes.
My Wu is always called the weakest, but...
not one person has ever died in it.
（澤圭）
今まで１人も死んでいません
（尾平･尾到）１人も？
（澤圭）はい
Not one?!
Yes.
弱者には弱者の戦い方があります
５人が10歩と離れず―
Weaklings have their own way of fighting.
The 5 of us must not get more than 10 steps apart,
常に 背を向け合い
死角を互いに埋めます
always watch each other's backs, and cover each other's blind spots.
守りが５人なら 攻めも５人
We'll have 5 people attacking as well as 5 people defending.
手負いの敵１人に対しても
５人で攻撃する　これは―
Even against 1 wounded opponent, all 5 of us attack.
This is not cowardice, it is a strategy.
卑怯(ひきょう)ではなく 戦法です
The five of us will be one body.
“五身一体” 私たちは
伍の結束で 生き残りましょう
With the bond of the Wu, we'll survive.
Five as one body...
五身一体…
（尾平）伍の結束…
Bond of the Wu...
あっ そうか
Oh, yeah.
なんか 妙に気持ちいいと思ったら
I thought it felt kinda weird.
いちばん先頭で
大軍勢を率いてるみたいだからか
I guess it's because being on the front lines feels like leading a huge army.
（尾平）
バカか お前！ こんなときに
Are you an idiot?! At a time like this?!
I see. So this is how being a general feels...
なるほど　将軍ってのは
こんな感じなんだろうな
I-In these circumstances... aren't you afraid...?
お前
こんな状況で 怖くねえのかよ？
Afraid?
怖い？
Naw... I've been waiting forever for this moment...
ああ 俺は
ずっと この時を待ってたからな
Xin...?
信…
（ドラの音）
な… 何だ？
W-What was that?!
（澤圭）突撃の号令が下ります
（信）えっ？
They're giving the order to charge!
Focus hard so you don't trip
気負って転ばないように
味方に踏み殺されます
or you'll be trampled to death by our allies!
（尾到）は… 始まる
It-It's starting...
Dammit! We're gonna do this! We're gonna do this!
（尾平）ちくしょう
やってやる… やってやるぞ！
いよいよ始まるぞ
ちゃんと見てっか？ 漂(ひょう)
It's finally starting...
Are you watching, Piao...?
全軍 構え！
All units, take your positions!
（信）そして 待ってろよ
And... wait for me... Zheng!
政(せい)！
全軍 突撃ーっ！
All units, charge!
お… おい あれ
Hey, over there!
( Flags - Wei )
（沛浪(はいろう)）
チッ… やっぱり そう来たか
I knew they'd be here!
It's a rock formation!
（沛浪）魏の岩陣だ！
てめえら 前のヤツらの屍(しかばね)
駆け上がって あの壁 乗り越えろ！
You guys have to run over the corpses of the guys in front
to get over that wall!
Otherwise we'll be crushed to by both in front and behind us!
さもなきゃ
前後から挟まれて つぶされるぞ！
（脇次）へ… へい！
（尾平）信！
（尾到）何を！
Xin?!
What're you doing?!
Young Xin!
（澤圭）信君！
（魏兵）なんか ガキが来るぞ！
（魏兵）殺せ殺せー！
Some kid's coming!
Kill him! Kill him!
（魏兵）ウワッ！
K-Kill him!
こ… 殺せー！
（魏兵たち）ヒイッ！
This guy's moving forward!
（魏兵）ぶっ殺しちまえ！
兄貴！
（尾平）あっ！
Big Brother!
（信）ヤッ！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
（尾平）信！
（歩兵）オッ！ あそこが開いたぞ
Xin!
That spot opened up!
壁が開いてる！
（歩兵）開いてるぞ！
There's an opening in the wall!
It's open!
ヘッ… 来い！
C'mon!
（魏兵）ウワッ…
アアッ… 兄貴！
Big Brother!
（尾平）到！
（斬る音）
Dao!
Wuchang!
（尾平）ご… 伍長！
（澤圭）２人とも 今です！
You two, now!
（魏兵）この卑怯者がー！
You cowards!
うるせえ！
これが俺たちの戦い方だ！
Shut up! This is the way our Wu fights!
（刺す音）
（魏兵）ウワッ！
What's with this...?
何だ？
もう息が上がってきやがった
I'm already really excited.
初陣で力んでんのか？
いや それだけじゃねえな
Is it because this is my first campaign?
No... That's not the only reason.
いつもより体が重い
いや 空気が重いんだ
My body's heavier than it usually is...
No, the air is what's heavier...
So this is a battlefield?!
これが戦場か…
大したことねえな！
This is nothin'!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）完璧(かんぺき)と思われた魏の岩陣
Wei's rock formation was thought to be perfect...
だが
信の開けた たったひとつのキズに
But with the one wound Xin opened up
なだれ込んだ兵の勢いは止まらず
the rush of soldiers that flooded in without stopping
緒戦の流れは
完全に秦国軍へと傾いた
and the flow of the beginning of the battle tilted utterly towards the Qin army.
Wei Army Vice Commander Gong Yuan
Or so it seemed.
…かに見えた
Xin!
（尾平）信！
（信）おう
（尾平）無事だったか
You're okay?!
（信）
アハハッ… 生きてたか 尾平
So you survived, Wei Ping?
“アハハ”じゃねえよ！
１人で思いっきり先走りやがって
Quit laughing! You rushed in there all by yourself!
兄貴…
Big Brother...
Didn't you hear what the Wuchang said?!
伍長の話 聞いてなかったのかよ！
伍の結束がだな…
About the bond of a Wu...
（澤圭）尾平さん いいんです
（尾平）伍長…
Wei Ping, it's all right.
Wuchang...
彼が
１人で突っ込んでくれなかったら
If he hadn't plunged in alone like that,
we may have been killed in the impact in the front lines.
我々は 最初の衝突で
死んでいたかもしれません
自分が皆のためにできることをする
これも 立派な伍の戦い方ですよ
He did what he could for everyone else.
It was also an incredible Wu battle strategy.
（尾到）ところで…
（２人）うん？
By the way...
Can you hear something?
何か聞こえないか？
（尾平）ああ？
It's like the ground is rumbling...
なんか 地鳴りのような…
（尾平）そういや魏の兵もいねえな
And where's the Wei Army, anyhow?
（地鳴り）
あ～ くそ　土煙で よく分かんねえ
Shit! I can't tell with all the dust.
この音は…
皆さん 気をつけてください！
Everyone, please be careful!
This is...
これは…
（２人）ハッ…
こ… これは なに？ うん？ うん？
Wh-What is this?
戦車隊… 魏が
中華最強と自負する装甲戦車隊です
The chariot corps!
It's an armored chariot unit boasting the strongest in all of China!
I can't believe they've sent them out this early!
こんなに早く出してくるとは
（信）ンンッ…
あの爆走してる馬に 正面から
行ったら 粉々になっちまう
If those rampaging horses came head-on...
we'd be pulverized!
斜めから攻めるにしても
上のほうが圧倒的に有利
And with them attacking from a slope, they'll have an overwhelming advantage coming from above!
しかも 失敗したら あの車輪の餌食
And if we fail, we'll be prey for those wheels.
手の出しようがねえ！
We've got no way through!
ボケッとしてんじゃねえ！
（尾平）うん？
Don't space out!
（体当たりの音）
（尾平たち）ウワッ！
Ow...
大丈夫か？
（澤圭）助かりました
You okay?
You saved us...
（尾平）早く下りてくれ　いてて…
（信）チッ…
Hurry, get down. Ow...
Shit! They got cocky!
くそ… ヤツら 調子に乗りやがって
The rumbling stopped, was that the end of it?
（尾到）地鳴りが やんだ…
今のが最後だったのか？
（尾平）半分… いや
もっと やられちまった ちくしょう
Half... No, more than that got killed! Dammit...
（澤圭）
恐らく これからが本番です
It's likely that the main attack has yet to come.
魏の戦車隊の本隊は 第２波と
聞いたことがあります　恐らく―
I've heard that Wei's chariot corps' main attack is the second wave.
It'll probably be such a huge army that we'll have nowhere to run...
逃げ場のないくらいの大軍で
掃討に来るはず
Th-That can't be...
そ… そんな…
（尾到）
き… 来てる！ あれ全部 戦車？
Th-They're coming!
Those... are all chariots?!
（尾平）
どどど… どうするよ？ アア…
W-W-W-What do we...
どうすりゃいいんだよ！
（信）くそ…
What do we do?!
Shit!
I have a plan.
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）策がある
（信たち）うん？
お前…
You...
You're still alive?!
生きてたのか
てっきり 姿が見えねえから…
I'd totally lost track of you...
それより 策って何ですか？ 羌瘣君
Anyhow, what do you mean, plan? Young Qiang Lei?!
（羌瘣）防壁を作る
（澤圭）ハッ…
We make a defensive wall.
Pile up the corpses.
（羌瘣）死体を積んで
し… 死体？
（尾到）積む？
Th-The corpses?
Pile up?
（沛浪）なるほど
I see.
Mr. Pei...
（澤圭）沛さん
（沛浪）悪くねえ思いつきだ
It's not a bad idea.
You guys, help out, too!
お前らも手伝え
盾と槍(やり) もっと拾ってこい！
Grab more shields and spears!
（戦車隊長）
ハハハッ！ 殺せ殺せ！
Kill! Kill!
秦国の犬ども
１匹残らず肉片にしてやれ！
Cut every last one of those Qin dogs into bits of meat!
ハハハハッ！ 子犬がいたぞ
There's a little puppy!
After him! Crush him to pieces!
追え追え！ ひきつぶしてしまえ！
What is this?!
何のマネだ？ そんなもので
戦車が止められると思ったか！
Do they think they can stop chariots with things like that?!
試してみろよ 馬車野郎！
（澤圭）信君 頭下げて！
Just try it, you carriage bastard!
Young Xin, lower your head!
（戦車隊長）死ねー！
Die!
ヤツら よけた！
（沛浪）無事か？ お前ら
They avoided us!
Are you guys all right?!
大丈夫だ　かすっただけだ
We're fine!
They just grazed us!
The other guys are all avoiding us, too!
ほかの所のヤツも
みんな よけていってやがる
やった！ ヤツら この中にいれば
手も足も出ねえぞ！
All right! As long as we're in here, they can't do a thing!
でかした 羌瘣！ お前のおかげだ
（歩兵）待て！
You did it, Qiang Lei!
It's all thanks to you!
Wait! Some of 'em are coming back!
戻ってくる連中がいるぞ
（歩兵）旋回してる？
They're turning around?!
They're aiming for us!
俺たちを狙ってんだ！ ヤバイ
壁のない裏から攻められたら…
Uh-oh! If they attack from behind where there's no wall...
（沛浪）バカ
You idiot! They won't turn back until after the main unit's gone through!
旋回してるのは
本隊が抜けるまで来ねえ
今は 前に集中してろ！
（澤圭）あっ！
Concentrate on the front right now!
投げ槍が来ます！
（沛浪）ンンッ…
Javelins are coming!
ヒイッ… 危なかった
That was close!
Dammit! Ying! Hang in there! Hey!
（脇次）
ちくしょう！ 栄(えい) 死ぬな！ おい！
Dammiiiit!
ちくしょー！
くそ！
Shit!
（羌瘣）戦車の速度が落ちてる
The chariots' speed is declining.
障害物… 防壁のせいだ
It's because of the obstacles... our defensive walls.
今なら狙える
Now they can aim.
（歩兵）アアッ！ また来た！
They're back!
（沛浪）おびえんな！
あと少しで本隊が抜ける！
Don't get scared!
Just a little more and we'll be through the main unit!
（信）尾平 これ持ってろ
（尾平）えっ？
Wei Ping, hold onto this!
一体 何を…
（澤圭）信君 戦車が来ます！
What're ya gonna do?
Young Xin! The chariots are coming!
頭を下げて！
Get your heads down!
Don't look down on me, you bastards!
ナメてんじゃねえぞ てめえら！
（尾平）信！
Xin?!
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
He did it!
（歩兵）やった！
And he's still alive!
（歩兵）
まだ生きてる　やっちまえ！
That's revenge for Ying, you bastards!
（歩兵）
栄の敵(かたき)だ この野郎！ 死ね！
Die!
こいつ…
（歩兵）よっしゃ！
This is...
All right!
We beat Wei's armored chariots!
魏の装甲戦車を倒したぞ！
（歩兵）やったんだ！
We did it!
（羌瘣）騒ぐな！
（歩兵たち）あっ…
Don't get excited!
旋回していた別隊が来る
A different unit that has turned around is coming.
（歩兵）わざわざ旋回した ヤツら
They went out of their way to turn back for us...
Are they intent on not letting a single one of us get away?
あいつら １人も逃がさねえ気か
（歩兵）ちくしょう…
防壁は前にしかねえのに
Dammit! We've only got a defensive wall facing forward!
結局 死ぬのかよ…
味方の騎馬隊は何やってんだよ！
So we're just gonna die after all?
What the hell are our mounted units doing?!
Have they just abandoned us?!
ヤツら 俺らを見捨てやがったのか
（信）そんなもん
最初から期待してんじゃねえよ！
You can't expect anything like that from the start!
自分の生きる道は 自分で切り開く
それだけだろう
You've gotta cut out your own path to survival!
That's all there is to it!
（尾平）お… お前 何やってる？
W-What're you doing?
馬に乗れるのか？ 小僧
You can ride a horse, kid?!
ヘヘッ… まあな
んなことより いいか？ みんな
Yeah, sorta.
But anyhow, listen up, everybody!
生き残るためには
あの戦車隊と戦うしかねえんだ！
If we wanna survive, our only choice is to fight those chariot corps!
だけど どうやって あんなのと…
（信）知るか！
But how do we fight those things?!
How would I know?!
そんなもん分かんねえけど
今は固まってねえで もがくときだ
I don't know how,
but if we don't solidify ourselves now, we'll struggle!
とにかく 時間を稼ぐ
Anyhow, I'll buy time!
みんなは できるだけ防壁を広げて
逃げ場を作れ！ まずは そっからだ
Everyone else, spread the defensive walls as much as you can so we have refuge!
We'll start from there!
ちょ… ちょっと待てよ
お前 まさか―
H-Hang on a second! You're not saying...
１人で
あの戦車の群れと戦うつもりかよ？
you're gonna go take on that swarm of chariots on your own, are you?!
Don't worry.
心配すんな
死にに行くわけじゃねえ
I ain't going there to die!
この戦い 絶対に勝つぞ！
（馬のいななき）
We're going to win this battle!
ハアッ！
（歩兵）よし 急げ！
ほかの伍のヤツらも手伝わせろ！
Okay, hurry!
We need the people from the other Wu to help out!
（脇次）よっしゃ！
（沛浪）槍と盾 拾ってこい！
All right!
Go grab more spears and shields!
防壁をできるだけ大きくするんだ！
（澤圭）皆さん お願いします！
We've got to make the wall as big as possible!
Thank you, everyone!
Xin... You're incredible.
（尾平）信… お前 すげえよ
( Flag - Qin )
（壁）前線は どうなっている？
What's happening on the front lines?!
この砂煙では 前が全く見えん
With all this sand in the air I can't see a thing!
突撃命令は まだか？
Has the order to charge come yet?!
待機の旗が揚がったままです
（壁）ンンッ…
They still have the standby flag raised!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）信たち第４軍の歩兵が
While Xin and the others, the foot soldiers of the 4th Army,
魏軍の歩兵
そして戦車隊と激しく戦っている中
the foot soldiers of Wei, and the chariot corps are fighting a fierce battle
戦場後方にいる秦国騎馬隊は
いまだ １騎も動いていなかった
not one of the State of Qin's mounted units have moved at all.
There is a lack of visibility due to the sand clouds,
砂塵(さじん)によって 状況が見えない
…という点もあったが 何より―
but the biggest reason is that the order to attack has yet to come from the main army's General Biao Gong.
本陣 麃公(ひょうこう)将軍よりの攻撃指令が
届いていなかったためである
ンンッ…
前線の戦況を確認しに行く
Bi Unit, we're going to check on the situation on the front lines!
壁隊！
（縛虎申）待て！
Wait!
そんなことは
貴様のやることではない
That is not a choice for you to make.
勝手に 持ち場を離れるな
Do not leave your post on your own accord!
Fu Hushen...
縛虎申…
（壁）不可解な命令だ　何か伝令に
問題があったのかもしれぬ
That order is nonsensical.
There may be a problem giving the signal.
決めつけるな
全て 麃公将軍の策のうちだ
That's not for you to decide.
Everything goes according to General Biao Gong's plan.
どんな策だ？
And what plan is that?!
歩兵を見殺しにする気か！
（縛虎申）おい
Do you intend to just let our soldiers die?!
Hey.
貴様は 歩兵を助けるために
わざわざ戦場に来たのか？
Did you come to this battlefield for the purpose of saving foot soldiers?
それとも
魏軍に勝利するために来たのか？
Or did you come in order to gain victory over the Wei Army?
Which is it?!
どっちだ！
（魏兵）
逃げろ逃げろ 子ウサギが！
Keep running, little rabbit!
左だ！ 左から寄せろ！
（笑い声）
The left! Cut him off on the left!
チッ！
図に乗りやがって 戦車野郎どもが
These chariot bastards are pushing their luck too far!
That was close!
あっぶねえ！
木の竿(さお)だったら やられてた
If this were a wooden poll, I would have been killed!
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
ヒイッ！
Even though they extended the walls, they're not protecting them at all!
防壁 広げても 完全には防げてねえ
結局 このままじゃ いずれ全滅する
攻めないと道はねえ
If this keeps up, we'll eventually be wiped out!
Our only choice is to attack!
It's no good!
ダメだ… 地上なら
何人でも どうってことねえが
If they were all on the ground it wouldn't be a big deal,
戦車と騎馬じゃ 足場が違い過ぎる
but on chariots and horses, their footing is just too different!
Should I jump on?!
飛び移るか？
いや あの車輪のせいで近づけねえ
No!
With those wheels, I can't get close!
ダメか… やっぱ
信でも戦車には かなわねえのかよ
Is it no good?
I knew it, even Xin can't stand up to those chariots...
Don't get distracted!
（羌瘣）気を散らすな！
（信）ハッ…
あいつ…
Him!
さっき倒した１台を思い出せ
お前の相手は戦車そのものだ
Remember the one you defeated earlier!
Your opponent is the chariot itself!
戦車そのもの？
The chariot itself?
そうだ　騎馬の機動力があれば…
（尾平･尾到）あっ…
That's right!
As long as you have the mobility from your horse...
ンンッ！
（盾に ぶつかる音）
さっきの１台？
The one from before?
そうか！
That's it!
戦う相手を間違えてた！
I've been fighting the wrong opponent!
（馬のいななき）
ハアッ！
隊長 馬のガキが来ます
（戦車隊長）うん？
Captain!
The kid on the horse is coming.
フン！ 小うるさいハエが
Annoying fly...
このわし自ら 葬ってくれるわ！
I'll bury him myself!
騎馬の機動力
そして この鉄の槍なら… いける！
With the mobility of the horse...
and this iron spear... I can do it!
お前らに用はねえ
I'm not interested in you guys!
My opponent is...
俺の相手は―
ムカつく戦車そのものだ！
this shitty chariot, itself!
反撃開始だ！
Now the counterattack begins!
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
～♪
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
（縛虎申）縛虎申隊 出撃ーっ！
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）走れ！ 振り向くな！
命あるかぎり 前だけを見ろ！
I won't cry
次回 “烈火の戦い”
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Preview
Fu Hushen Unit, charge!
Run! Don't turn back!
As long as you're alive, face only forward!
A Blazing Battle
Next time,
End